<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<!-- http://brussels.gmfus.org/ -->
<agenda>
	<splash url="splash.png"/>
	<event>
		<id>1</id>
		<title>Europe in Transition</title>
		<summary>Europe in Transition</summary>
		<content>
		Europe has undergone a number of transitions at key points in its history: 100 years ago, World War I; 25 years later, the continent entered a dark period of its history with the arrival of the Nazis taking Europe into World War II. But in its aftermath, Europe has witnessed unprecedented levels of political, economic, and social integration. When the Berlin Wall came down in 1989, Europe welcomed a new era in its history bringing East-West rivalry to an end and allowing for the unification and integration of a formerly divided continent.
		This period has given way to a new phase characterized by integration on one hand and increasing division and uncertainty on the other. Europe is struggling to find its way out of multiple crises. Challenges persist not only in the sovereign debt markets and banking sectors, but in societies and political systems. The economic and social models of a number of member states are under severe pressure. The European elections may reveal dissatisfaction and voters’ strong support for populists may put European and national policymakers under pressure. Meanwhile, a new crisis is looming on Europe’s eastern borders.
		Today, Europe is at another crossroads, facing growing opportunities and responsibility to take leadership on the world stage while having to cope with strong political pressure, the risk of social unrest at home, and new conflicts on the continent. Against this backdrop, national and European policymakers must frame new policy approaches and lead profound change both within the EU and in its external relations. These changes will shape the future of Europe in the decades to come and in turn determine its role on the global stage.
		</content>
		<date>22-JUL-2014 09:00</date>
		<duration>1:40</duration>
		<popularity>3</popularity>
		<presenterId>1</presenterId>
		<url>http://www.themoviedb.org/person/287</url>
		<images>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-original.jpg" size="original" width="1295" height="1969" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-profile.jpg" size="profile" width="185" height="281" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-thumb.jpg" size="thumb" width="45" height="68" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
		</images>
		<location>Hall 92</location>
		<last_modified_at>2010-10-24 10:22:10</last_modified_at>
	</event>
	<event>
		<id>2</id>
		<title>NATO in Transition</title>
		<summary>NATO in Transition</summary>
		<content>
		Since NATO’s founding 65 years ago, a great deal of history has been made in Europe. The Berlin Wall went up, the Berlin Wall came down, the Soviet Union collapsed, Germany reunited, and the Eastern Bloc nations joined the Alliance and the European Union. NATO engaged in “out of area” operations first in the Balkans and then in Afghanistan and assisted with disaster relief in areas far from the traditional borders of Europe. And, on September 12, 2001, the Alliance, for the first and only time in its history, invoked Article V of the 1949 Washington Treaty, which supports the use of force to protect signatory nations, after the United States was attacked by al Qaeda.
		At the end of this year, with the end of the combat mission in Afghanistan, NATO, for the first time in 20 years, will not be engaged in any major out-of-area military operations. For some, the idea of a “peace dividend” is very attractive. For others, the idea of an “operational pause” will allow their armed forces to properly reset and restock itself and prepare for the next mission. And yet a third group will continue to stay engaged in military operations, whether it will be in the form of supporting EU missions, UN missions, national missions, or NATO maritime missions, thus requiring continued equipping and modernization of their militaries.
		The recent Ukraine crisis with Russia has certainly raised the importance of answering the question of just what kind of NATO the Allies want post-2014. Prior to the events of the past month, the debate and discussion was mixed: return to the roots of a territorial-focused NATO or remain engaged as an organization who seeks to engage itself globally where actions threaten the well-being of the transatlantic community? Hold off on enlarging NATO to new aspirants for a few more years or welcome those who have been trying to join the Alliance and have made the necessary reforms in order to show the two-decade old policy of a “Europe whole, free, and at peace” still is in force? Accept that there are capability gaps such as air-to-air refueling, strategic lift, and ISR but that, as long as the United States is part of the Alliance, it will cover those deficiencies and NATO can conduct the necessary missions or truly develop some European capacity by investing in these enablers so that Europe can do more on its own if it wanted to as well as be a better partner to the United States?
		</content>
		<date>22-JUL-2014 12:00</date>
		<duration>1:50</duration>
		<popularity>3</popularity>
		<presenterId>2</presenterId>
		<url>http://www.themoviedb.org/person/287</url>
		<images>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-original.jpg" size="original" width="1295" height="1969" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-profile.jpg" size="profile" width="185" height="281" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-thumb.jpg" size="thumb" width="45" height="68" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
		</images>
		<location>Hall 92</location>
		<last_modified_at>2010-10-24 10:22:10</last_modified_at>
	</event>
	<event>
		<id>3</id>
		<title>Can Europe Grow Again?</title>
		<summary>Can Europe Grow Again?</summary>
		<content>
		The economic situation in Europe remains frail. In 2013, overall growth in the European Union was stagnant. There were positive signs in the second half of the year as the eurozone finally emerged from its long recession, but growth numbers have varied significantly across member states, and questions regarding the sustainability of the economic recovery, particularly in the EU’s periphery, persist. Sovereign debt and unemployment levels remain high and questions about the state of Europe’s banks ahead of this summer’s stress test are adding further worries. In many countries, significant reform packages are being discussed and some implemented. But many of these reforms may only deliver economic gains in the long-term, if at all. Some core countries, like Germany, have seen solid economic performances, but can they function as growth engines for the rest of Europe? In light of these developments, this session will assess the current state of Europe’s economic recovery.		</content>
		<date>22-JUL-2014 14:00</date>
		<duration>1:50</duration>
		<popularity>3</popularity>
		<presenterId></presenterId>
		<url>http://www.themoviedb.org/person/287</url>
		<images>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-original.jpg" size="original" width="1295" height="1969" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-profile.jpg" size="profile" width="185" height="281" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
			<image type="profile" url="http://hwcdn.themoviedb.org/profiles/00e/4bc977ad017a3c182400000e/brad-pitt-thumb.jpg" size="thumb" width="45" height="68" id="4bc977ad017a3c182400000e"/>
		</images>
		<location>Hall 92</location>
		<last_modified_at>2010-10-24 10:22:10</last_modified_at>
	</event>
</agenda>